National Arts Club
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Administration, 1898-1960, undated, Series 2:
  - President, 1917-1957, undated, 2.4:
    For additional information relating to the records in this subseries see Series 2.1: Officers' Correspondence, War Tax Refund and Mortgage Bonds; Series 3: Financial Records; and Series 8.1, Treasurer's Reports.
    - Treasurer's Notebook Volume 1, 1917-1919 (Reel 4253, Frame 48-163)
    - Treasurer's Notebook Volume 2, 1919-1922 (Reel 4253, Frame 164-311)
    - Treasurer's Notebook Volume 3, 1922-1926 (Reel 4253, Frame 312-461)
    - Treasurer's Notebook Volume 4, 1926-1931 (Reel 4253, Frame 462-552)
    - Treasurer's Notebook Volume 5, 1931-1934 (Reel 4253, Frame 553-632)
    - Treasurer's Notebook Volume 6, 1934-1938 (Reel 4253, Frame 633-703)
    - Treasurer's Notebook Volume 7, 1938-1940 (Reel 4253, Frame 704-776)
    - Working Papers, 1918-1931, (1 volume) (Reel 4253, Frame 777-921)
    - Working Papers, 1918-1931, cont., (1 volume) (Reel 4254, Frame 11-29)
    - Purchase of Internal Revenue Stamps (Act of Oct. 22, 1914), 1917 (Reel 4254, Frame 30-77)
    - Correspondence re: Taxes, 1932, 1938-1939 (Reel 4254, Frame 78-117)
    - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1943-1957 (Reel 4254, Frame 118-366)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Reel 4254, Frame 367-371)
  - Manager, 1956-1960, 2.5:
    This series concerns arrangements for events held at the Club (both NAC and non-NAC sponsored), restaurant, accommodations for members visiting from out of town, and use of gallery space with detailed schedules for 1957-1958.
    - Correspondence (filmed twice), 1956-1960 (Reel 4254, Frame 374-1161)
  - House Committee, 1922-1932, 2.6:
    This subseries contains correspondence about house rules, condition of the building, and the needs and problems of residents and those renting studios.
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1922-1932 (Reel 4254, Frame 1165-1445)
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1922-1932, cont. (Reel 4255, Frame 4-384)
  - American Artists' War Emergency Fund Committee, 1917-1918, 2.7:
    The correspondence found here mainly concerns issuing stamps to raise money for financial aid to art workers suffering financial reverses due to the war and to help increase food production for the country at large. Included are sample stamps designed by Eugene Savage, and printed matter of the American Artists' War Emergency Fund Committee.
    - Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Reel 4255, Frame 387-481)
  - Men's Open Table, 1915-1950, 2.8:
    Correspondence found in this subseries concerns the selection of speakers, comments by members about programs, some announcements of meetings, and printed matter about speakers. The noices of Men's Open Table meetings comprise one announcement per page, accompanied by signatures of members in attendance; also included are Ipson sketches of speakers: Dr. Elwood Hendrick, April 26, 1928; Prof. J.W. Jenks, Feb. 14, 1927; Col. Norman Schwartzkopf, Dec. 5, 1927; Gregory Zilboorg, March 12, 1928; and of members Billy [Hutchinson], Dec. 5, 1927, and Mason Chase, Jan. 16, 1928. There is also the poem, "To the Mens Open Table," by Frank Chapin Bray, Nov. 1926.
    For related information see also Series 8.1: National Arts Club Printed Matter and Series 9: Scrapbooks.
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1915-1916, 1918 (Reel 4255, Frame 485-700)
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1922-1929 (Reel 4255, Frame 701-1215)
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1922-1929, cont. (Reel 4256, Frame 4-550)
    - Miscellaneous (Reel 4256, Frame 551-587)
    - Dinner in honor of William S. Hutchinson, 1928 (Reel 4256, Frame 588-618)
    - "Memories of the Men's Open Table of the National Arts Club," by John R. Gregg, 1941 (Reel 4256, Frame 619-651)
    - Notices of Men's Open Table meetings, Volume 1, 1919-1925 (Reel 4256, Frame 652-766)
    - Notices of Men's Open Table meetings, Volume 2, 1925-1929 (Reel 4256, Frame 767-981)
    - Notices of Men's Open Table meetings, Volume 2, 1942-1950 (Reel 4256, Frame 892-934)
- Financial Records, 1917-1952, Series 3:
  This series contains general ledgers and cashbooks, accounts of special funds, and Treasurer's reports. Correspondence of the Treasurer and other officers is especially thorough regarding application for and use of a refund of war tax levied on membership dues in 1917/18, and concerning First and Second Mortgage Bonds issued to finance the clubhouse. For additional information relating to these records see Series 2.1: Officers Correspondence, War Tax Refund and Mortgage Bonds; and Series 8.1: National Arts Club Printed Matter, Treasurer's Reports.
  - Special Fund, December 1917, (1 volume) (Reel unfilmed)
  - Ledgers, 1922-1927, 1939-1949, (2 volumes) (Reel unfilmed)
  - Treasurer's Monthly Statements, 1923-1929, (1 volume) (Reel unfilmed)
  - General Cash Books, 1939-1946, 1946-1952, (2 volumes) (Reel unfilmed)
  - Cash Receipts, 1947-1949, (1 volume) (Reel unfilmed)
  - Account Book, 1949-1950, (disbound volume) (Reel unfilmed)
- Membership, circa 1900-1962, Series 4:
  Records consist of membership rolls from 1940 to 1952 (11 volumes), and rosters from 1931 to 1959. Membership rosters contain alphabetical listings by name, including address, telephone number, category of membership, and date of election, with notes on date and reason for discontinuation of membership. For additional information relating to these records see Series 2.3: Secretary and Series 8.1: National Arts Council Printed Matter, Membership Lists.
  Membership rolls are arranged by membership category; rosters are arranged alphabetically
  - Membership Rolls (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 1: Resident, Junior Lay, Younger Artists, Suburban, May 1940-May 1942 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 2: Resident, Junior Lay, Younger Artists, Suburban, May 1942-May 1944 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 3: Non-Resident Priviledged, Non-Resident, Associate, May 1942-May 1944 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 4: Non-Resident Priviledged, Non-Resident, Associate, May 1944-May 1946 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 5: Resident, Junior Lay, Younger Artists, Suburban, May 1944-May 1946 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 6: Non-Resident Priviledged, Non-Resident, Associate, May 1946-May 1948 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 7: Resident, Junior Lay, Younger Artists, Suburban, May 1946-May 1948 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 8: Resident, Junior Lay, Younger Artists, Suburban, May 1948-May 1950 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 9: Non-Resident Priviledged, Non-Resident, Associate, May 1948-May 1950 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 10: Non-Resident Priviledged, Non-Resident, May 1950-May 1952 (Reel unfilmed)
    - Volume 11: Resident, Junior Lay, Junior Artists, Suburban, Associate, May 1950-May 1952 (Reel unfilmed)
  - Membership Rosters (Reel 4256)
    - circa 1900 (Reel 4256, Frame 942-1054)
    - circa 1900, cont. (Reel 4257, Frame 4-28)
    - 1931 (Reel 4257, Frame 30-285)
    - 1932 (Reel 4257, Frame 287-474)
    - 1932-1934 (Reel 4257, Frame 476-682)
    - 1936-1938 (Reel 4257, Frame 684-876)
    - 1947 (some pages out of order) (Reel 4257, Frame 878-1123)
    - 1950 (Reel 4257, Frame 1125-1372)
    - 1951-1952 (Reel 4257, Frame 1374-1426)
    - 1951-1952, cont. (Reel 4258, Frame 4-118)
    - 1951-1952, cont. (Reel 4258, Frame 121-368)
    - 1952-1956 (Reel 4258, Frame 370-586)
    - 1953-1954 (Reel 4258, Frame 588-797)
    - 1956-1962 (Reel 4258, Frame 799-1022)
    - 1958 (Reel 4258, Frame 1024-1217)
    - 1959 (Reel 4258, Frame 1219-1238)
    - 1949-1950 (target incorrectly reads 1959) (Reel 4258, Frame 1239-1433)
    - 1949-1950, cont. (Reel 4259, Frame 4-69)
- Arts Realty Co., 1909-1913, 1945-1956, undated, Series 5:
  This small group of records is extant. For additional information relating to the Arts Realty Co. see Series 2.1: Officers' Correspondence, Mortgage Bonds.
  - List of Stockholders (Reel 4259, Frame 73-76, 81)
  - Resolution of Board of Directors, 1909 (Reel 4259, Frame 77)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1910 (Reel 4259, Frame 78)
  - Stock Certificates (Reel 4259, Frame 79-80)
  - Correspondence regarding mortgage bonds, 1913 (Reel 4259, Frame 81-183)
  - Minutes of Stockholders' Meetings, 15 Gramercy Park, Inc., 1945-1956, (1 volume) (Reel 4259, Frame 184-344)
- Miscellaneous, 1890-1961, undated, Series 6:
  This series includes various legal documents, material predating establishment of the National Arts Club, unpublished speeches delivered at the Club, information about clubhouses occupied, and histories of the organization.
  Letters predating the establishment of the club include copies of letters concerning French military equipment and de Kay to J.Q.A. Ward outlining plans for founding a society of sculptors. Speeches include addresses delivered at the Annual Thanksgiving Dinner by Walter S. Logan in 1905; at a dinner in honor of Spencer Trask in 1908; by the Ambassador of Indonesia in 1953; by President Talcott at a reception in honor of the art students of New York, undated; and "The Future of the Horse" by Charles de Kay, also undated. Records on clubhouses include the lease for 156 Fifth Ave. (first office of National Arts Club); lease for 37 West 34th St., and longitudinal section of alterations to NAC, 37 West 34th St. (first clubhouse); maps of Gramercy Park; floorplan of the Grille Room showing placement of tables; and a fact sheet and miscellaneous notes concerning the Tilden Mansion (present clubhouse).
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1898, 1961 (Reel 4259, Frame 350-367)
  - Constitution of the National Arts Club, 1900 (Reel 4259, Frame 368-379)
  - Letters Predating Establishment of the National Arts Club, 1890-1897 (Reel 4259, Frame 380-390)
  - Speeches (see also Series 8.1: National Arts Club Printed Matter, Speeches), 1905-1953; undated (Reel 4259, Frame 391-460)
  - Biographical Notes on Gates Douglas Fahnestock (1853-1936) and Samuel J. Tilden (1814-1886), undated (Reel 4259, Frame 466-473)
  - Library notes and lists, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 466-473)
  - Facts and Figures concerning the National Arts Club, circa 1947 (Reel 4259, Frame 474-549)
    (includes lists of artwork missing from the permanent collection, governors with dates of election, and priviledged societies)
  - Histories of the National Arts Club, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 550-610)
  - Drawings, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 611-620)
    (Old Dutch Grille; 7 drawings of costumes for Gramercy Park pageant by A. Garfield Learned)
  - Donations to Piano Purchase Fund, undated, (on illuminated sheet) (Reel 4259, Frame 621-622)
  - Calendars of Events/Programs, Invitations (not printed), 1955/56-1956/57 (Reel 4259, Frame 623-629)
  - Clubhouses, 1898-1899, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 630-640)
  - Miscellaneous Legal Documents (relating to real estate), 1911-1930 (Reel 4259, Frame 641-671)
- Photographs, 1899-1957, undated, Series 7:
  This series is organized into nine subseries:
  7.1: People, undated
  7.2: Exhibitions, Gallery Installations and Works Exhibited, 1899-1957
  7.3: Works of Art, undated
  7.4: Building, undated
  7.5: Events, 1931-1956, undated
  7.6: Miscellaneous, undated
  7.7: Negatives, 1910-1921, undated
  7.8: Album, 1910-1921, undated
  7.9: Oversized, undated
  Photographs of individuals are filed alphabetically by category: Officer, Governors, and Life Members; Artists; and Others. Group photographs are categorized as identified and unidentified, and arranged in chronological order. Exhibition installation shots are arranged chronologically, and photos of works of art are alphabetized by name of artist. Interior and exterior views of the National Arts Club building are arranged in rough chronological order, as are pictures of events. An album contains: views of exhibition installations, 1910-1917, in chronological order, and a few portraits of prize recipients and artist members, 1917-1921. Oversize photos follow.
  - People, undated, 7.1:
    Photographs of officers, governors, and life members include: John C. Agar, Charles Coburn, Bird S. Coler, Shubael Cottle, E. Irving Couse, Gates D. Fahnestock, Oscar Fehrer, J. William Fosdick, John R. Gregg, Harold Howland, Chester Loomis, John Clude Oswald, George B. Post, F.W. Ruckstuhl, and Frank R. Towle. Photographs of artists include: H.R. Bacher, Hilda Belcher, Louis Betts, Isabel Bishop, George Elmer Browne, Gordon Grant, Daniel Greene, Mauno Oittinen, Leon Volkmar, and Harry Voorhees. Photographs of others include Alistair Cooke, David Nadien, Mrs. Leonard Tyson Scully, Mrs. Alfred Chappell, and Eleanor Wendell.
    - Officers, Governors, and Life Members, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 675-722)
    - Artists, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 724-754)
    - Others, Unidentified, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 755-789)
    - Groups, Unidentified and Identified, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 790-815)
  - Exhibitions, Gallery Installations and Works Exhibited, 1899-1957, 7.2:
    - Gold and Silver Exhibition, Oct. 1899 (Reel 4259, Frame 817-821)
    - Members' Exhibition, April 1908 (Reel 4259, Frame 822-828)
    - Art Students League Exhibition, May 1908 (Reel 4259, Frame 829-835)
    - Third Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, Nov. 1908 (Reel 4259, Frame 836-840)
    - International Exhibition of Pictorial Photography, Feb. 3-20, 1909 (Reel 4259, Frame 841-844)
    - John W. Alexander Retrospective, March 1909 (Reel 4259, Frame 845-861)
    - Exhibition of the New York Society of Keramic Arts, April 1909 (Reel 4259, Frame 862-870)
    - Fourth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, Dec. 1910 (Reel 4259, Frame 871-881)
    - Walter Shirlaw Memorial Exhibition, March 8-April 5, 1911 (Reel 4259, Frame 882-886)
    - Group Exhibition: William R. Derrick, Gifford Beal, Reynolds Beal, and Frederick J. Waugh, April-May 1911 (Reel 4259, Frame 887-897)
    - Exhibition of Color Schemes and Model Rooms in Miniature, Oct. 25-Nov. 4, 1911 (Reel 4259, Frame 898-902)
    - Sixth Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, Nov. 8-30, 1911 (Reel 4259, Frame 903-911)
    - Fifth Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, Dec. 1911 (Reel 4259, Frame 912-914)
    - Otto Walter Beck Exhibition, Feb. 1912 (Reel 4259, Frame 915-917)
    - Sculpture Exhibition, May 1912 (Reel 4259, Frame 918-920)
    - Sixth Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, Dec. 4-28, 1912 (Reel 4259, Frame 921-922)
    - Applied Arts of Germany, March 12-31, 1913 (Reel 4259, Frame 924-926)
    - Seventh Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, Dec. 3-28, 1913 (Reel 4259, Frame 927-937)
    - Hungarian Peasant Art, March 11-29, 1914 (Reel 4259, Frame 938-943)
    - Annual Exhibition of Small Sculpture, May 6-31, 1914 (Reel 4259, Frame 944-958)
    - Members' Exhibition, June-Oct. 1915 (Reel 4259, Frame 959-961)
    - Loan Exhibition of Portraits of Academicians and Associates Selected from the Permanent Collection of the National Academy of Design, March 2-25, 1916 (Reel 4259, Frame 962-965)
    - Twentieth Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, Nov. 1925 (Reel 4259, Frame 966-969)
    - Decorative Arts Exhibition, Dec. 1929 (Reel 4259, Frame 970-998)
    - Eighth Annual Exhibition by Living American Etchers, Dec. 3-26, 1930 (Reel 4259, Frame 999-1001)
    - Thirty-second Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, Nov. 1937 (Reel 4259, Frame 1002-1004)
    - Exhibition of Indonesian Art, March 1953 (Reel 4259, Frame 1005-1014)
    - Fiftieth Anniversary Exhibition of Books of the Year, 1956 (Reel 4259, Frame 1015-1018)
    - International Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture, June 1957 (Reel 4259, Frame 1019-1025)
    - Arts and Crafts Exhibitions, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1026-1044)
    - Annual Exhibitions of Books of the Year, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1045-1052)
    - Ceramic Art Exhibition, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1053-1055)
    - Pottery Exhibition, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1056-1058)
    - Traveling Exhibition of Enlarged Photographs of Sculpture and Spring Exhibition of Small Sculpture by Members of the National Sculpture Society, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1059-1065)
    - Exhibition of Small Sculpture, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1066-1067)
    - Exhibition of Still Life and Flower Paintings in Oil, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1068-1070)
    - Unidentified Exhibitions, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1071-1107)
  - Works of Art, undated, 7.3:
    The photographs in this subseries are of works of art that were, presumably, exhibited at the National Arts Club or belong to the Club's permanent collection. Works of art pictured are by artists including Edmund John Archer, C.H. Barr, Alexander Franham, Charles W. Hawthorne, Anna Hyatt Huntington, Marianthe Karaberi, La Duble, Allen G. Newman, Mauno Oittinen, Jo Paddock, and Annabelle E. Williams.
    - Works of Art, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1108-1196)
  - Building, undated, 7.4:
    This subseries contains photographs of the exterior and the interior of the National Arts Club building.
    - Exterior, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1197-1210)
    - Interior, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1211-1227)
  - Event, 1931-1956, undated, 7.5:
    This subseries contains photographs of various National Arts Club events. For additional photographs in this category see Series 7.8: Album, and Series 7.9: Oversize, Mural Decorations in the Galleries (Mi Careme Festival)
    - New Year's Eve Carnival, 1931 (Reel 4259, Frame 1230-1232)
    - Faith Baldwin speaking at the Thirty-second Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, 1937 (Reel 4259, Frame 1233-1235)
    - Wild West Costume Ball, 1939 (Reel 4259, Frame 1236-1242)
    - Twenty-fifth Annual Exhibition and Members Dinner, Society of American Etchers, 1940 (Reel 4259, Frame 1243-1246)
    - Charles Coburn and Boris Bogdanovitch at War Bond Auction, circa 1943 (Reel 4259, Frame 1247-1249)
    - Ruth Renfrew and Florence Duryea with Greek dolls, 1947 (Reel 4259, Frame 1250-1254)
    - Opening of the Fiftieth Anniversary Exhibition, 1948 (Reel 4259, Frame 1255-1262)
    - Presentation of award to Huntington Hartford at Fifty-eighth Annual Exhibition, Dinner for Artist Members, 1956 (Reel 4259, Frame 1263-1264)
    - Decorations by Junior Members for New Year's Eve Party, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1265-1271)
    - Demonstration at Old Mill Art School, Elizabethtown, N.Y., undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1272-1274)
    - Unidentified, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1275-1308)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, 7.6:
    This subseries contains photographs of an unidentified house and of the National Arts Club medal of honor. For additional photographs in this category see Series 7.8: Album.
    - National Arts Club Medal of Honor, House, undated (Reel 4259, Frame 1309-1312)
  - Negatives, undated, 7.7:
    This subseries contains negatives that were not microfilmed.
    - Negatives, undated (Reel Unfilmed)
  - Album, 1910-1921, undated, 7.8:
    This subseries contains 1 disbound volume containing photographs of exhibition installations from 1910 to 1917 and photographs of people and events dating from 1917 to 1921.
    - Third Annual Exhibition of Advertising Art, 1910 (Reel 4260, Frame 6-8)
    - Fourth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, 1910 (Reel 4260, Frame 9-10, 12)
    - First Annual Exhibition of the Work of Artist Life Members, 1911 (Reel 4260, Frame 11, 13-14)
    - Exhibition of the New York Society of Keramic Arts, 1911 (Reel 4260, Frame 15-18)
    - Walter Shirlaw Memorial Exhibition, 1911 (Reel 4260, Frame 19-22)
    - Color Schemes and Model Rooms in Miniature, 1911 (Reel 4260, Frame 26-28)
    - Group Exhibition, 1911 (Reel 4260, Frame 23-25)
    - Fifth Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, 1911 (Reel 4260, Frame 32-34)
    - Sixth Annual Book Exhibition, 1911 (Reel 4260, Frame 29-31)
    - Otto Walter Beck, 1912 (Reel 4260, Frame 38-40)
    - Etchings of T. E. Hurley, 1912 (Reel 4260, Frame 41, 46-47)
    - Pictures of National Parks, 1912 (Reel 4260, Frame 42-44)
    - Emerson McMillan Collection, 1912 (Reel 4260, Frame 45, 48-52)
    - Members' Special Prize Exhibition, 1912 (Reel 4260, Frame 35-37)
    - Sculpture Exhibition, 1912 (Reel 4260, Frame 53-55)
    - Exhibition of Industrial Art (Art Dept. of the City High Schools), 1912 (Reel 4260, Frame 56-58)
    - Annual Exhibition of the Society of Illustrators, 1912 (Reel 4260, Frame 59-61)
    - Sixth Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, 1912 (Reel 4260, Frame 62-64)
    - Works of Frederick W. Freer, 1913 (Reel 4260, Frame 68-70)
    - Members' Special Prize Exhibition, 1913 (Reel 4260, Frame 65-67)
    - Applied Arts of Germany, 1913 (Reel 4260, Frame 71-73)
    - Group Exhibition, 1913 (Reel 4260, Frame 74-76)
    - Sculpture Exhibition, 1913 (Reel 4260, Frame 77-79)
    - Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, 1913 (Reel 4260, Frame 80-82)
    - Painter Members Exhibition, 1914 (Reel 4260, Frame 83-86)
    - Hungarian Peasant Art, 1914 (Reel 4260, Frame 87-90)
    - Group of Western Painters, 1914 (Reel 4260, Frame 91-93)
    - Sculpture, 1914 (Reel 4260, Frame 94-97)
    - Eighth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, 1914 (Reel 4260, Frame 98-101)
    - Painter Members Exhibition, 1915 (Reel 4260, Frame 102-104)
    - Exhibition of the American Water Color Society, 1915 (Reel 4260, Frame 105-109)
    - Ninth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, 1915 (Reel 4260, Frame 110)
    - Painter Members Exhibition, 1916 (Reel 4260, Frame 111-112)
    - National Academy of Design Loan Exhibition of Portraits, 1916 (Reel 4260, Frame 115-116)
    - Exhibition of American Water Color Society, 1916 (Reel 4260, Frame 113-114)
    - Members' Annual Exhibition, 1917 (Reel 4260, Frame 117-118)
    - Exhibition of Books of the Year, 1917 (Reel 4260, Frame 119-120)
    - Twelfth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, 1917 (Reel 4260, Frame 123-125)
    - Medals, undated (Reel 4260, Frame 120-121)
    - Portrait of Mme. Signe Lund, winner of prize for best patriotic music, 1917 (Reel 4260, Frame 122)
    - Portrait of Daniel Henderson, winner of prize for best patriotic music, 1917 (Reel 4260, Frame 122)
    - F. Luis Mora making part of a frieze for New Year's Eve Carnival, 1920 (Reel 4260, Frame 126)
    - Group of artists working on frieze, [1920?] (Reel 4260, Frame 129-130)
    - Ernest L. Ipsen making poster for New Year's Eve Carnival, 1920 (Reel 4260, Frame 126)
    - Group portraits of members attending New Year's Eve Carnival, 1920/21 (Reel 4260, Frame 127-134)
    - Edwin Booth Memorial, Gramercy Park, undated (Reel 4260, Frame 135)
  - Oversize, undated, 7.8:
    For additional photographs relating to mural collections in the galleries see Series 7.8: Album.
    - Mural Decorations in the Galleries (Mi Careme Festival),undated (Reel 4260, Frame 136-138)
- Printed Matter, 1893-1960, undated, Series 8:
  Printed matter is organized into two subseries:
  8.1: National Arts Club Printed Matter, circa 1900-1960, undated
  8.2: Non-National Arts Club Printed Matter, 1893-1959, undated
  Series 8.1 is arranged by record type. Series 8.2 is organized by subject, with the exception of clippings which are arranged chronologically.
  - National Arts Club Printed Matter, circa 1900-1960, undated, 8.1:
    Yearbooks include the constitution, by-laws, house rules; lists of members, officers, and committees; and lists of exhibitions and lectures presented. The books are illustrated with pictures of the clubhouse, exhibitions, and events. Bulletins contain calendars of events, lists of newly elected members, and news of members. The 1909, 1914, and 1939-1940 issues include pictures of exhibition installations, the clubhouse interior including the restaurant and men's grill, social events, and prizewinning art work. Brochures contain general information for guests and prospective members. Many are illustrated with views of the building, exhibitions, and social events. Of particular interest is the 1906 brochure which contains a description of the new clubhouse with floorplans.